http://www.eraa.org/policy

Skip to main content
You are here: Home
Privacy Policy
DATA PRIVACY POLICYThe ERA (European Regions Airline Association) is a not for profit trade association representing European aviation. This policy explains when and why we collect personal information about our members, persons that use its website and how we use it and keep it secure and your rights in relation to it.ERA uses and protects any information that you give ERA when you become a member of the association and including when you use its website www.eraa.orgERA is committed to ensuring that your privacy is protected. Should we ask you to provide certain information by which you can be identified when using this website, then you can be assured that it will only be used in accordance with this privacy statement.ERA reserves the right to amend this policy from time to time without prior notice. You are advised to check the ERA website www.eraa.org from time to time to for any amendments.WHAT WE COLLECTWe collect information to enable us to• to administer and manage the membership of the association and provide services and respond to queries as part of membership;• to promote and provide information to members about our events and work groups and to send newsletter and information;• to ensure the billing for any services provided and obtain payment;• process application for employment; and• to enable us to meet our legal obligationsThe information we need for this purpose is personal data and includes your name, job title, address (es), email address (es), telephone contact numbers, financial information and photographs/promotional images of attendees participating at our networking events and work groups.HOW WE COLLECT THIS INFORMATIONWe collect this information in a variety of ways. For example, you may provide this information on a membership application form, an event registration or booking form, via email, visiting our website, over the telephone or by letter.WHAT WE DO WITH THE INFORMATION WE GATHERWe require this information for the purposes detailed below:Purpose for processing data / Legal basis for processing dataTo administer and manage the members membership of the association / Performing the association’s contract with the membership and for the legitimate interests of operating the associationTo hold and a run member conferences and groups for members of the association including follow up surveys related to the events / For the legitimate interests of holding these events as a membership organisation for the benefit of members; for the purposes of our legitimate interests in operating and promoting the associationCreating and managing the association’s website,  online membership directory, yearbook and publications / Performing the association’s contract with the membership. Consent will be sought on the member’s application form. Consent for which can be withdrawn at any time by contacting us by email to inform us they no longer wish their details to be includedTo communicate with you on member news, industry news, event invitations which are relevant to you  / Performing the association’s contract with the membership. To also seek consent prior to sending non association member individuals information and in line with their preferencesRecruitment of association employees / For the legitimate interests of operating the associationEnter into and managing arrangements with suppliers / For the legitimate interests of operating and promoting the associationTo administer the association’s relationship with you and respond to queries / Consent will be sought to retain informationHOW WE PROTECT YOUR PERSONAL DATAWe are committed to ensuring that your information is secure. In order to prevent unauthorised access or disclosure, we have implemented generally accepted standards of technology and operational security in order to protect personal data from loss, misuse or unauthorised alteration or destruction. For any payments which we take from you online we will use a recognised online secure payment system. We will not transfer your data out of the European Economic Area (EEA)WHO ELSE HAS ACCESS TO THE INFORMATION YOU PROVIDE US?We will not sell, distribute or lease your personal data to third parties unless we have your prior consent (which you can withhold) or are required by law to do so except:• we may pass your personal data to third parties who are service providers, agents and subcontractors to us for the purposes of completing tasks and providing services to you on our behalf eg print publications. We do this for the purposes of our legitimate interests in operation the association and for performing our contract with you. We only disclose the information that is necessary for the third party to deliver the service and we will have a contract in place that requires them to keep your information secureHOW LONG WILL WE RETAIN YOUR INFORMATION We will hold your data on our systems for as long as you are a member of the association and for as long afterwards as is necessary to comply with our legal obligations. We will securely destroy all financial information once we have used it no longer need it.HOW WE USE COOKIESA cookie is a small file which asks permission to be placed on your computer's hard drive. Once you agree, the file is added and the cookie helps analyse web traffic or lets you know when you visit a particular site. Cookies allow web applications to respond to you as an individual. The web application can tailor its operations to your needs, likes and dislikes by gathering and remembering information about your preferences.We use traffic log cookies to identify which pages are being used. This helps us analyse data about web page traffic and improve our website in order to tailor it to customer needs. We only use this information for statistical analysis purposes and then the data is removed from the system.Overall, cookies help us provide you with a better website, by enabling us to monitor which pages you find useful and which you do not. A cookie in no way gives us access to your computer or any information about you, other than the data you choose to share with us.You can choose to accept or decline cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. This may prevent you from taking full advantage of the website.LINKS TO OTHER WEBSITESOur website may contain links to other websites of interest. However, once you have used these links to leave our site, you should note that we do not have any control over that other website. Therefore, we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information which you provide whilst visiting such sites and such sites are not governed by this privacy statement. You should exercise caution and look at the privacy statement applicable to the website in question.YOUR RIGHTSYou have rights under the GDPR:• to access your personal data;• to be provided with information about how your personal data is processed;• to have your personal data corrected;• to have your personal data erased in certain circumstances;• to object or restrict how your personal data is processed;• to have your data transferred to yourself or to another business in certain circumstances; and• you have the right to lodge a complaint with the information Commissioner’s Office who may be contacted at www.ico.org.uk.If any of the information we hold about you is inaccurate or you have any concerns or complaints about the way in which your personal data has been handled you can write to our Data Protection Officer at European Regions Airline Association, Park House, 127 Guildford Road, Lightwater, Surrey, GU18 5RA or by email at info@eraa.orgMay 2018
